Guide to the J. Walter Thompson Company. Chicago Office. Elna Cederholm papers, 1955-1973 and undated RL.11773
David M. Rubenstein Rare Book & Manuscript Library
J. Walter Thompson Company. Chicago Office. Elna Cederholm papers
1955-1973 and undated
David M. Rubenstein Rare Book & Manuscript Library
J. Walter Thompson Company. Chicago Office
RL.11773
0.4 Linear Feet
Founded in 1864, the J. Walter Thompson Company (JWT) is one of the oldest and largest enduring advertising agencies in the United States. It is headquartered in New York. The Chicago Office opened in 1891. Elna Ann Cederholm was an account representative with the JWT Chicago office in the 1960s and 1970s. Collection includes personal and professional correspondence, travel souvenirs along with work documents pertaining to Cederholm's career as an account representative for JWT on Oscar Mayer advertising campaigns. Acquired as part of the John W. Hartman Center for Sales, Advertising & Marketing History.
Biographical / Historical
Founded in 1864, the J. Walter Thompson Company (JWT) is one of the oldest and largest enduring advertising agencies in the United States. It is headquartered in New York. The Chicago Office opened in 1891. Elna Ann Cederholm was an account representative with the JWT Chicago office in the 1960s and 1970s.
Elna Ann Cederholm born 1940, Indiana. AA, Stephens College (Theatre, Radio and Television) 1960, BA Michigan State University (Communications) 1963. JWT Chicago: Traffic Coordinator 1963-1970; Account Representative 1970-approximately 1974. Left JWT approximately 1974, married JWT executive Ed George 1974. Died 2014 Florida.
Access Restrictions
Collection is open for research.
Provenance
The J. Walter Thompson Company. Chicago Office. Elna Cederholm papres were received by the David M. Rubenstein Rare Book & Manuscript Library as a gift in 2015. The papers were removed from the J. Walter Thompson Company Ed George papers.
Related Materials
Related materials may be found in the following Hartman Center collections:
J. Walter Thompson Company. Account files
J. Walter Thompson Company. Ed George papers
J. Walter Thompson Company. Domestic Advertisements collection
Collection Overview
Collection includes personal and professional correspondence, travel souvenirs along with work documents pertaining to Cederholm's career as an account representative for JWT on Oscar Mayer advertising campaigns. Acquired as part of the John W. Hartman Center for Sales, Advertising & Marketing History.
Advertising; Advertising -- United States; Advertising agencies; Advertising agencies -- United States -- History; Women in the advertising industry; Cederholm, Elna Ann; George, Ed; Oscar Mayer & Co
- Personal and Professional Files, 1955-1973 and undated; 1
  - Cards and notes, 1967-1973 and undated (Box 1)
  - Correspondence and general, 1964-1973; 3 folders (Box 1)
  - Correspondence--From Davie Wilkerson, 1961-1963 (Box 1)
  - Correspondence--From Draper & Kramer, 1969-1971 (Box 1)
  - Correspondence--From Edward Tannenbaum, 1962 (Box 1)
  - Correspondence--From Robert Reid, 1955-1960 (Box 1)
  - J. Walter Thompson--Oscar Mayer account, 1970-1973 (Box 1)
  - Los Angeles memorabilia, 1971 and undated (Box 1)
    Scope and Contents
    Includes: Hamm's cartooon drawn on napkin; hand-drawn map
  - New York memorabilia, 1964-1970 and undated (Box 1)
    Includes: Postcards, Empire State Building, Drake Hotel, play guides (Coco, Fiddler on the Roof, Oh Calcutta!)